JANE M. HSU

Hawthorne, CA 90250 | (206) 240-2154 | jane99hsu@gmail.com https://github.com/plainjane99 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/jane-hsu-7329b497

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Entry-level web developer with engineering, project management, and leadership experience who is motivated by a love of learning. Broad knowledge in multiple programming languages and frameworks for the development of full-stack applications. Well-rounded engineering background provides an excellent foundation for delivering inclusive solutions. Organized, detail-oriented, and collaborative nature allows thorough execution and delivery of quality products.

TECHNICAL & LEADERSHIP HIGHLIGHTS

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React | Bootstrap | JQuery | Node.js | Express | MySQL | Express | MongoDB

- **Strategic** Transformed an engineering and manufacturing organization for effective and efficient design, fabrication, modification, and test of engineering test fixtures.
- **Execution** Designed the plan, oversaw the personnel, and coordinated the logistics across multiple disciplines in the execution of multi-million-dollar statements-of-work.
- **Leadership** Mentored junior and senior-level engineers in understanding new technologies and their application to enable them to take ownership of their projects. Advocated for resources that resulted in empowered and engaged personnel.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Northrop Grumman Corporation, El Segundo, CA, 07/2003 – Present

- Staff System Engineer Lead Engineer responsible for \$60M+ over 5 years for the design, fabrication, modification, and test of multiple large-scale test fixtures. Responsible for managing cost and schedule, developing resource plans, mentoring team, collaborating with stakeholders, managing suppliers, and coordinating with test facilities for most efficient and cost-effective solutions. 2018 Present
- Functional Manager Championed development initiatives for improved employee engagement. Managed the performance development, assessment, and review of a team of 20 employees. 05/2015 2018
- \bullet Principal System Engineer Designed and analyzed platform features and materials for performance and application onto full scale platforms. 05/2011-05/2015
- Principal Mechanical Engineer Led the structural design effort of a large-scale test fixture. Designed small-scale fixtures for data acquisition. 05/2008 05/2011
- Principal Mechanical Engineer Designed primary composite structure for flying platforms under an expedited schedule. Worked closely with NC Programming to manufacture complex parts. 07/2003 – 05/2008

EDUCATION

Full Stack Web Development Extension Course, February 2021 University of California Los Angeles, Los Angeles, CA

Bachelor of Science, Mechanical Engineering, December 2000 University of Washington, Seattle, WA